//objects for questions and answers
//store questions in an array of objects [{question, ans1, ans2, ans3, ans4, correct answer]
var questionList = [
    {question: "In 1768, Captain James Cook set out to explore which ocean?",
    opt1: "Pacific Ocean",
    opt2: "Atlantic Ocean",
    opt3: "Indian Ocean",
    opt4: "Arctic Ocean",
    ans: "Pacific Ocean"},
    {question: "What is actually electricity?",
    opt1: "A flow of water",
    opt2: "A flow of air",
    opt3: "A flow of electrons",
    opt4: "A flow of atoms",
    ans: "A flow of electrons"},
    {question: "Which of the following is not an international organisation?",
    opt1: "FIFA",
    opt2: "NATO",
    opt3: "ASEAN",
    opt4: "FBI",
    ans: "FBI"},
    {question: "Which of the following disorders is the fear of being alone?",
    opt1: "Agoraphobia",
    opt2: "Aerophobia",
    opt3: "Acrophobia",
    opt4: "Arachnophobia",
    ans: "Agoraphobia"},
    {question: "Which of the following is a song by the German heavy metal band “Scorpions”?",
    opt1: "Stairway to Heaven",
    opt2: "Wind of Change",
    opt3: "Don’t Stop Me Now",
    opt4: "Hey Jude",
    ans: "Wind of Change"},
    {question: "What is the speed of sound?",
    opt1: "120 km/h",
    opt2: "1,200 km/h",
    opt3: "400 km/h",
    opt4: "700 km/h",
    ans: "1,200 km/h"},
    {question: "Which is the easiest way to tell the age of many trees?",
    opt1: "To measure the width of the tree",
    opt2: "To count the rings on the trunk",
    opt3: "To count the number of leaves",
    opt4: "To measure the height of the tree",
    ans: "To count the rings on the trunk"},
    {question: "What do we call a newly hatched butterfly?",
    opt1: "A moth",
    opt2: "A butter",
    opt3: "A caterpillar",
    opt4: "A chrysalis",
    ans: "A caterpillar"},
    {question: "In total, how many novels were written by the Bronte sisters?",
    opt1: "4",
    opt2: "5",
    opt3: "6",
    opt4: "7",
    ans: "7"},
    {question: "Which did Viking people use as money?",
    opt1: "Rune stones",
    opt2: "Jewellery",
    opt3: "Seal skins",
    opt4: "Wool",
    ans: "Jewellery"},
    {question: "What was the first country to use tanks in combat during World War I?",
    opt1: "France",
    opt2: "Japan",
    opt3: "Britain",
    opt4: "Germany",
    ans: "Britain"},
    {question: "What is the main component of the sun?",
    opt1: "Liquid lava",
    opt2: "Gas",
    opt3: "Molten iron",
    opt4: "Rock",
    ans: "Gas"},
    {question: "Goulash is a type of beef soup in which country?",
    opt1: "Hungary",
    opt2: "Czech Republic",
    opt3: "Slovakia",
    opt4: "Ireland",
    ans: "Hungary"},
    {question: "Which two months are named after Emperors of the Roman Empire?",
    opt1: "January and February",
    opt2: "March and April",
    opt3: "May and June",
    opt4: "July and August",
    ans: "July and August"},
    {question: "Which of the following animals can run the fastest?",
    opt1: "Cheetah",
    opt2: "Leopard",
    opt3: "Tiger",
    opt4: "Lion",
    ans: "Cheetah"},
    {question: "Where did the powers of Spiderman come from?",
    opt1: "He was born with them",
    opt2: "He was bitten by a radioactive spider",
    opt3: "He went through a scientific experiment",
    opt4: "He woke up with them after a dream",
    ans: "He was bitten by a radioactive spider"},
    {question: "What is the most points that a player can score with a single throw in darts?",
    opt1: "20",
    opt2: "40",
    opt3: "60",
    opt4: "80",
    ans: "60"},
    {question: "In the United States, football is called soccer. So what is American football called in the United Kingdom?",
    opt1: "Rugby",
    opt2: "American football",
    opt3: "Handball",
    opt4: "Combball",
    ans: "American football"},
    {question: "Which of the following actors was the first one to play James Bond?",
    opt1: "Timothy Dalton",
    opt2: "Roger Moore",
    opt3: "Sean Connery",
    opt4: "George Lazenby",
    ans: "Sean Connery"},
    {question: "Which of the following songs was the top-selling hit in 2019?",
    opt1: "Someone You Loved",
    opt2: "Old Town Road",
    opt3: "I Don’t Care",
    opt4: "Bad Guy",
    ans: "Someone You Loved"},
];